[
  
  
      {
        "question": "An absolute ruler unrestrained by law is?",
        "choice1": "Tyrant",
        "choice2": "Oligarchy",
        "choice3": "Helots",
        "choice4": "Ephor",
        "answer": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "A government in which a small group has control",
        "choice1": "Tyrant",
        "choice2": "Oligarchy",
        "choice3": "Helots",
        "choice4": "Ephor",
        "answer": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "A government by the people",
        "choice1": "Tyrant",
        "choice2": "Oligarchy",
        "choice3": "Democracy",
        "choice4": "Ephor",
        "answer": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "Enslaved people in Ancient Sparta",
        "choice1": "Tyrant",
        "choice2": "Oligarchy",
        "choice3": "Helots",
        "choice4": "Ephor",
        "answer": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "A high-ranked government official in Sparta who was elected by the council of elders.",
        "choice1": "Tyrant",
        "choice2": "Oligarchy",
        "choice3": "Helots",
        "choice4": "Ephor",
        "answer": 4
      },
      {
        "question": "Around 600 B.C. the political unrest among city-states led this type of leader to take power? ",
        "choice1": "Ephor",
        "choice2": "tyrants",
        "choice3": "helots",
        "choice4": "oligarchy",
        "answer": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "the founders of Sparta were the descendents of the __________",
        "choice1": "Romans",
        "choice2": "soldiers",
        "choice3": "Dorians",
        "choice4": "spartans",
        "answer": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "Spartan women were trained in what",
        "choice1": "Sports",
        "choice2": "Wrestling",
        "choice3": "throwing the javelin",
        "choice4": "all of the above",
        "answer": 4
      },
      {
        "question": "Sparta used their _____________ to prevent future revolt",
        "choice1": "military",
        "choice2": "brains",
        "choice3": "muscles",
        "choice4": "women",
        "answer": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "The founders of Athens were the descendants of ___________",
        "choice1": "spartans",
        "choice2": "mycenaeans",
        "choice3": "italians",
        "choice4": "Americans",
        "answer": 2
      },
    {
      "question": " A form of democracy in which citizens elect officials to govern on their behalf",
      "choice1": "Direct Democracy ",
      "choice2": "Representative Democracy",
      "choice3": "Indirect Democracy",
      "choice4": "Philosopher ",
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "A form of democracy in which all citizens can participate firsthand in the decision-making process ",
      "choice1": "Direct Democracy ",
      "choice2": "Representative Democracy",
      "choice3": "Indirect Democracy",
      "choice4": "Philosopher ",
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "A person who searches for wisdom or enlightenment",
      "choice1": "Direct Democracy ",
      "choice2": "Representative Democracy",
      "choice3": "Indirect Democracy",
      "choice4": "Philosopher ",
      "answer": 4
    },
    {
      "question": "Under whose leadership did Athens experience a Golden Age?",
      "choice1": "Ceasar ",
      "choice2": "God",
      "choice3": "Athena",
      "choice4": "Pericles ",
      "answer": 4
    },
    {
      "question": "who could attend school in Athens",
      "choice1": "boys",
      "choice2": "girls",
      "choice3": "everyone",
      "choice4": "men",
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "whose role in Athnes was to learn how to read, play music and teach at home?",
      "choice1": "Men",
      "choice2": "women",
      "choice3": "grandparents",
      "choice4": "children ",
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "The Athenian economy was based on what?",
      "choice1": "Farming",
      "choice2": "Trade",
      "choice3": "all of the above",
      "choice4": "none of the above ",
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the group that served as a protective and defensive league?",
     "choice1": "Spartan",
      "choice2": "Athens",
      "choice3": "Mob",
      "choice4": "Delian ",
      "answer": 4
    },
    {
      "question": "who fought in the peloponnesian war?",
      "choice1": "Sparta and Athens",
      "choice2": "Greece and Athens",
      "choice3": "Sparta and Greece",
      "choice4": "Athens and America",
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "The Athenian __________ was based on farming and trade",
      "choice1": "life",
      "choice2": "Economy",
      "choice3": "Culture",
      "choice4": "Housing",
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "What form of Democracy is when the citizens elect officials to govern on their behalf",
      "choice1": "Representative",
      "choice2": "Indirect",
      "choice3": "Direct",
      "choice4": "Human",
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "What form of Democracy is when all citizens can participate firsthand in the decision-making process",
      "choice1": "Representative",
      "choice2": "Indirect",
      "choice3": "Direct",
      "choice4": "Human",
      "answer": 3
    }
 ]
